<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="pretty-atom-feed.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>Margaret Fero&#39;s Blog</title>
  <subtitle>This blog contains content known to Margaret Fero.</subtitle>
  <link href="https://maggiefero.github.io/feed/feed.xml" rel="self" />
  <link href="https://maggiefero.github.io/" />
  <updated>2025-01-29T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <id>https://maggiefero.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Margaret Fero</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Reflections on the &#92;#IAmRemarkable Workshop</title>
    <link href="https://maggiefero.github.io/blog/iAmRemarkable/" />
    <updated>2025-01-29T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://maggiefero.github.io/blog/iAmRemarkable/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week I attended an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rmrkblty.org/iamremarkable&quot;&gt;#IAmRemarkable&lt;/a&gt; Workshop hosted by facilitator Amanda Ho Sang for participants from a handful of
tech leadership communities. In this workshop, we learned about the origin of #IAmRemarkable as a women-focused initiative at Google, and how it has since
grown into a movement for all to participate in building healthy self-promotional skills.
We heard about and discussed the benefits of fact-based self-promotion, and how we can create success for those around us by modeling it ourselves
through showing examples of our achievements instead of de-emphasizing them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout the workshop, we were invited to participate in exercises that encouraged us to think deeply about the ways we are each remarkable and what we have
already accomplished. We were further challenged to put theory into practice by sharing some of our accomplishments with the group, to help model that success
for those around us in the workshop. This was also a great opportunity to begin building muscle memory offering accomplishments up to a group instead of hiding them.
I&#39;m not sharing specific examples of others&#39; accomplishments in this post to protect
participants&#39; privacy, but will share general descriptions of what we learned from each other. My key takeaways from this experience were that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sharing accomplishments begets accomplishments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Self-promotion is important for more than just your own advancement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your accomplishments are not only professional.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;sharing-accomplishments-begets-accomplishments&quot;&gt;Sharing accomplishments begets accomplishments.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sharing your accomplishments gives others a clearer view into what you have been working on lately and what you&#39;ve done previously. This creates a more accurate
perception of your knowledge, skills, and abilities, which in turn empowers others to enlist your help as appropriate. If nobody knows you have worked in a field before, they
are less likely to invite you to participate in relevant future projects, and very unlikely to know when to pull you in for assistance on their own related projects or tasks.
This is one of the most commonly-discussed benefits of self-promotion, as a means of achieving personal advancement. The studies presented in this workshop, however, emphasized
the benefits to others of being able to enlist your assistance when appropriate, and highlighted how a sense of modesty can be a detriment to the team and business
in this context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;self-promotion-is-important-for-more-than-just-your-own-advancement&quot;&gt;Self-promotion is important for more than just your own advancement.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I knew at the start of the workshop that self-promotion is critical to personal advancement, I underestimated the impact that appropriate, fact-based
self-promotion can have on others. Promoting your achievements not only helps others who may be able to help you advance see what you&#39;ve been up to. It also helps
others with less or similar experience see the accomplishment you shared as an option available to them. Letting others see your accomplishments creates two significant
positive outcomes beyond yourself:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They can see their potential future self reflected in your accomplishments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They may see their past self reflected in your accomplishments, and realize they&#39;re underselling their own experience.
Both of these enable others to further their own achievement, and to share their own accomplishments more broadly. This underrated aspect of the importance of self-promotion
can enable greater advancement within our teams and communities. That advancement may occur through role modeling for less-experienced
people who see themselves in you and aren&#39;t sure where to go with their careers yet, or through helping people with as much or more experience realize what they&#39;ve already
done and should be sharing more of from their own background.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the course of this workshop alone, several of us realized that an accomplishment someone else promoted was also something we had done ourselves or
similar to one of our own accomplishments. Now we can go into the world with the confidence that this previously-overlooked experience of ours is valuable, and help others
realize that achievement as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;your-accomplishments-are-not-only-professional&quot;&gt;Your accomplishments are not only professional.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the exercises involved taking ten minutes to write a list of our own achievements, things we had done that make each of us remarkable. Going into this exercise, ten
minutes felt like a lot, but I was pleasantly surprised to fill the time fairly easily. When we reached the end of the time, though, we began to share examples from our lists
with the group to practice claiming our achievements out loud. The facilitator, Amanda, went first, and chose a personal example. That&#39;s when I realized there was only one
single non-work accomplishment on my entire list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In sharing her personal example, Amanda modeled valuing all of our achievements, both professional and beyond. Her example opened the door for me to notice a whole world of
achievements I had been overlooking, from kindness and supporting friends to making a positive impact in my communities in various ways. I think of all the takeaways
from the workshop, this one was the most valuable for me. It&#39;s so easy when talking about impact to let &amp;quot;impact&amp;quot; mean only &amp;quot;business impact&amp;quot;, when the effect of our work
often extends well beyond business impact and into interpersonal and social effects, for better or for worse. This exercise served as a gentle reminder to continue
to focus on measuring the full scope of our impact, rather than business impact alone. In measuring the full scope of our impact, we can ensure that our impact grows
in positive ways.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Setting SMART Research Objectives</title>
    <link href="https://maggiefero.github.io/blog/SMART-research-objectives/" />
    <updated>2025-01-21T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://maggiefero.github.io/blog/SMART-research-objectives/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This year, I&#39;m trying a different approach to planning my research goals. Rather than pick a general area to explore and see where it goes, as I often do, I&#39;m attempting to set myself SMART research objectives by targeting specific combinations of topic and conference proposal deadline. In case you&#39;re not familiar with SMART goals, &lt;a href=&quot;https://community.mis.temple.edu/mis0855002fall2015/files/2015/10/S.M.A.R.T-Way-Management-Review.pdf&quot;&gt;George T. Doran&#39;s original 1981 article&lt;/a&gt; introducing them is a dated but still valuable read. The acronym has somewhat shifted over time, and today mostly refers to goals that are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S&lt;/strong&gt;pecific, rather than overly-broad or general, because over-generality can make taking action more difficult&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;M&lt;/strong&gt;easurable, according to specific metrics you set up front&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;ttainable within the time you have and with the resources available to you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt;elevant to your team&#39;s (or in this case, my personal) goals and interests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;T&lt;/strong&gt;ime-Bound, rather than going on indefinitely&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SMART goals are no longer considered the best framework for team- or organization-level goal-setting, but I still really like them for my individual goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By using conference schedules as a scaffold for planning my research this year, I have applied the SMART framework to avoid letting the scope of my goals creep beyond what I&#39;m likely to achieve. I&#39;m really pleased with how my research objectives came out with this new methodology, so I thought I&#39;d share the four-step process!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;1-list-interesting-conferences&quot;&gt;1. List Interesting Conferences&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, I listed out conferences where I think it would be cool to submit something this year. I don&#39;t expect every proposal I submit to be accepted, but picking specific conferences I&#39;m interested in sharing things with gives me natural deadlines. This both ensures &lt;em&gt;Relevance&lt;/em&gt;, because they&#39;re events I know I would like to attend, and keeps things &lt;em&gt;Time-bound&lt;/em&gt;, because most of these events have predictable CFP deadlines. In some cases, the deadline has been announced. In other cases, I extrapolate from when the CFP has closed in previous years. In one case, the conference has a rolling CFP deadline, so I can fit it in flexibly around other research but certainly no later than a month before the event. At this stage, I didn&#39;t worry about what I might have to share, or what I might want to look into for a given conference in particular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;2-list-interesting-research-areas&quot;&gt;2. List Interesting Research Areas&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I had my list of interesting conferences, I set it aside and made a list of interesting topics. Some of these were general areas I&#39;m curious about exploring to see what I can find, while others were already &lt;em&gt;specific&lt;/em&gt; enough to be a research goal as-is. These included areas I wanted to compile new datasets in, areas where I wanted to analyze an existing dataset in a new way, and areas where I wanted to summarize what&#39;s already out there in a literature review or similar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favorite projects tend to involve analyzing existing datasets in new ways, so those were overrepresented on this list. I decided that&#39;s fine for my goals. I&#39;m mostly looking to learn some new things, help others solve problems, and have fun doing it. I&#39;m not as concerned about a balance of methodologies as I would be if this was workplace research on a single specific topic from a variety of angles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;3-map-research-areas-to-conferences&quot;&gt;3. Map Research Areas to Conferences&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, I mapped the two lists onto each other. Where the research areas list had something general, combining a research area with a conference&#39;s tone and focus often helped me narrow down the subject until I had something &lt;em&gt;specific&lt;/em&gt; for every area/conference combination. Each of these combinations is inherently &lt;em&gt;measureable&lt;/em&gt; as well, because the expected outcome for each area/conference combination is a CFP submission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of those will turn into talks, but having an audience in mind keeps the project focused even if it ends up not making the cut for this year&#39;s event. In some cases, multiple conferences have a similar enough vibe or the research isn&#39;t too of-the-moment so I can iterate on an unaccepted talk concept for future events. In a year where I had unaccepted talks from the previous year to iterate on, I would probably have planned some of those in at this stage as well. I don&#39;t have any right now, though, so this is a big new-project year for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;4-check-your-list-twice&quot;&gt;4. Check Your List Twice&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I had a list of projects I&#39;m curious about and audiences I think would be interested in hearing about what I find, it was time to go over that list one more time for the last aspect of SMART goals: &lt;em&gt;Attainability&lt;/em&gt;. One of the conferences already had their CFP deadline for this year, and I could submit something for next year but the project I thought that audience would enjoy relates to a current trend that might not be important any more by then. That one got eliminated as &lt;em&gt;unattainable&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also flagged a few where a dataset to be compiled or analyzed might be hard to pull together, and one where a costly tool I don&#39;t currently have a license for would be the best way to get the work done. These aren&#39;t necessarily off the list. For example, I might be able to obtain a software license by the time I need it, or there may be an easier way to compile some of the potentially-tricky datasets. I&#39;ve marked these risks and am not counting the related projects as goals I&#39;m committing to until I am able to get more information about their viability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The remaining projects were &lt;em&gt;attainable&lt;/em&gt;, and at this point each research concept had a SMART goal! From here, I can pretty easily break down the projects into phases. Then I&#39;ll create calendar blocks to dedicated time to work on each project, as well as reminders of milestones and deadlines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By setting research goals for the year based on areas of interest that I thought the audiences of specific conferences I want to attend would enjoy, I was able to ensure that my goals were Specific, Measureable, Relevant, and Time-bound by default. I also noted to myself which potential goals need further assessment of Attainability to see if they&#39;re worth committing to. From here, I&#39;ll break projects down and set reminders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you try this or a similar process, let me know how it goes! I&#39;d also love to hear about how you&#39;re deciding what to look into this year.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Hello, World!</title>
    <link href="https://maggiefero.github.io/blog/firstpost/" />
    <updated>2025-01-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://maggiefero.github.io/blog/firstpost/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is my first post on my first 11ty site. I was pretty confused going through the tutorial from the official documentation, but @phildini pointed me to the &lt;em&gt;immensely&lt;/em&gt; helpful repo &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/11ty/eleventy-base-blog/&quot;&gt;11ty/eleventy-base-blog&lt;/a&gt;, which got me back on track. Overall, I expect this site to contain a few things: my bio, this blog, videos and possibly summaries of some or all of my talks, and possibly if I really get my act together even my LinkTree as a subpage. Who knows what the future may hold!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>